Guide to the Kiev Foundation pamphlet collection, 1898-1979 K0004
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Kiev Foundation Pamphlet Collection
1898-2012
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
K0004
3 Linear Feet
The majority of the pamphlets concern antisemitism and sermons from prominent European and American rabbis. The pamphlets are dated from 1946-79.
Box 2
Box 1
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
The pamphlet collection consists of purchases made after the original donation of the I. Edward Kiev Judaica Collection in 1996 and are primarily gifts from the Kiev Family Trust, with some materials donated by Dr. Samuel Halperin.
Historical Note
The pamphlet collection consists of purchases made after the original donation of the I. Edward Kiev Judaica Collection in 1996 and are primarily gifts from the Kiev Foundation, with some materials donated by Dr. Samuel Halperin.
This is an open collection and materials continue to be actively acquired.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection consists of 3 linear feet of pamphlets purchased or donated after the original donation of the I. Edward Kiev Collection. There are about one hundred pamphlets in the series ranging in date from 1925 to 2012. The collection consists primarily of pamphlets concerning anti-Semitism and Holocaust denial, most of which were published by Liberty Bell Publications. There are also eleven issues of the American Standard, a bi-weekly anti-Semitic and anti-Catholic serial. Also included in the series are sermons from prominent European and American rabbis, reports from the Baron de Hirsch Trade School, and a French serial devoted to the Alfred Dreyfus trial of 1894.
Jews; Antisemitism; Holocaust, Jewish (1939-1945); Christianity; Propaganda; Rabbinical literature; Judaism; Sermons; London (England); Israel; Zionism; United States; Palestine; Great Britain; Goldstein, Israel; Christian Educational Association; Christian Nationalist Crusade; Catholic Church. Archdiocese of Munich and Freising (Germany); Catholic Church; America's Promise--The Alliance for Youth; Wolf, Lucien; Luther, Martin; Liberty Bell Publications; Kiev Foundation; Jewish National Fund; Hebrew Union College-Jewish Institute of Religion; Herzl, Theodor
- Talmud revival, 1950 ca. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- The architects behind the world Communist conspiracy, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Mystery manuscript: a chronology of the Zionist plan for world domination, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Beware of Herod. He would slaughter the Christ child. Bury Christ Permanently cry the Jews. Challenge: keep Christ in American culture, 12/21/1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Program of the National Renaissance Party, 1950 ca. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- The Jewish problem as dealt with by the Popes, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Jesus vs. the Jews, 1946-1946 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- The physical appearance of Jesus, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- I was branded with the number 666, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Jews on the wrong side of every major life and death issue, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- The Jews and their lies, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  General note
  Translated and published by the Christian Nationalist Crusade
- The Protocols of the Learned Elders of Zion, 1960 ca. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Translated by Victor E. Marsden from Sergyei Nilus (1905)
- The point, 1/1955 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- English journal reveals... Jewish control of A and H bombs, 1954-1954 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Originally published by Gothic Ripples (English journal) on June 29, 1954
- Anti-Semitism, a phoney bogey. Ideology, not race, causes trouble: even the Nazis respected Christianized Jews, 12/15/1963-12/15/1963 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Know your enemy, 1950-1950 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- An open letter to any minister who teaches the Jews are Israel, 1976-1976 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Why don't you believe what we tell you?, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
- The ultimate world order, as pictured in the Jewish utopia, 1957-1957 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Quotes! Quotes!! Quotes!!! Herein are quotations which only dedicated research has resurrected from the libraries of the world, 1963-1963 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- The Talmud unmasked: the secret Rabbinical teachings concerning Christians, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  Originally Published in St. Petersburg in Latin on April 13, 1892
- The Carter regime infested with Jews, 7/1979-7/1979 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Sample arithmetic vs. the 6 Million myth, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
- The liberty amendment: money trap, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  This is Anti-Communist, but publisher has also published Anti-Semitic pamphlets
- Official definition of democracy, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Who's who in the world Zionist conspiracy, 1/1978-1/1978 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- The World Hoax, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  With Introduction by William Dudley Pelley. 3 pamphlets in one: "Twilight Over England" by William Joyce w. Intro by Craig L. Fraser and "This Time the World" by George Lincoln Rockwell
- Power and propaganda in American politics and foreign affairs, 4/1978-4/1978 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- The record of European Jewry, 1950-1950 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  With a forward by Dr. Redcliffe N. Salaman, F.R.S. and an afterward by Rabbi I. I. Mattuck, A.M., Ph.D.
- Messianic expectations, 1886 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Communism is Irish, 3/1979 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  This is Anti-Irish, but publisher has also published Anti-Semitic pamphlets
- The Times history and encyclopaedia of the war, vol. 14, 1/15/1918 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- New Zionist publications, no. 3. Evidence submitted to the Palestine Royal Commission, 2/11/1937 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- A sermon delivered at the Spanish and Portuguese Jews' synagogue, Bevis Marks, 11/15/1850 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Catalog and program of the Hebrew Union College, 1902-1903 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Papers for Jewish people, no. 14. Religion and society, undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Official definition of democracy, undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Conference on restoration of continental Jewish museums, libraries and archives, 4/11/1943 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Jewish emancipation: the contract myth, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Lucien Wolf and Theodor Herzl, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Liberty Bell Publications Book price list no. 379, 8/1/1979 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Liberty Bell Publications order form, undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Report of the joint Palestine survey commission, 6/18/1928 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  Includes map
- Yes, six million did not die, 7/1978-8/1978 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- All aid to Palestine outpost of democracy, 11/1940 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- The Jewish Historical Society of England: preface, undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
  Reprinted from "Transactions," vol. 12
- ADL bulletin, 3/1985 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Flag raising, 10/21/1917 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Strictly kosher, undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Jewish ministers? An arraignment of American Reform Judaism, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  These articles appeared originally in the "Hebrew Standard" of New York and have been republished by request.
- In memoriam: Doctor Aaron Friedenwald 1836-1902, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Eighteenth report of the Baron de Hirsch trade school, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Frankfurter's red record, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Seventeenth report of the Baron De Hirsch trade school, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Sixteenth report of the Baron De Hirsch trade school, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Nineteenth report of the Baron De Hirsch trade school, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Twenty-second report of the Baron De Hirsch trade school, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Twenty-first report of the Baron De Hirsch trade school, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 59)
- Twenty-fifth report of the Baron De Hirsch trade school, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Twenty-sixth report of the Baron De Hirsch trade school, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 61)
- Cataloguue for the Baron De Hirsch trade school, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 62)
- Some legal difficulties which beset the Jewess, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  Accompanying the pamphlet is the addenda for the International Conference of Women Zionists, held in London in July, 1920.
- Casting of lots (a Purim party in one act), 1914 (Box 1, Folder 64)
- The passing of Jewey: an unrecorded incident of the Civil War, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 65)
- Eight pages related to the Baron De Hirsch Trade School, undated (Box 1, Folder 67)
  Includes a blank diploma.
- The Jew I want to be: a confirmation sermon, 05/31/1968 (Box 1, Folder 68)
- L'affaire Dreyfus, illustree: Et ses Ressorts secrets, no. 2-10, 10/28/1898-12/9/1898 (Box 1, Folder 69)
- L'affaire Dreyfus, illustree: Et ses Ressorts secrets, no. 11-20, 12/13/1898-1/13/1899 (Box 1, Folder 70)
- Selections from the prayerbook, second edition, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 71)
- The American Standard: vol. 2, no. 12-19, 20-24, 6/15/1925-12/15/1925 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  Bi-weekly
- Vstuplenie Bunda v" R.S.-D.R.P. [The Entry of the Bund into the RSDRP], c. 1915-1921 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  General
  Xerox of Russian pamphlet authored by Tsentralni Komitat Poale-Tsiyon, published by Knigoizdatel'stvo "Pereval"
- The Torch: vol. 34, no. 4, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  Published by National Federation of Jewish Men's Clubs, Inc.
- On the Redaction of Talmud by Chaim D. Regensburg, Kerem: vol. 2, no. 2, no year given (Box 1, Folder 74)
- The Disseminator, A Compendium of Abstracts in Religion, Philosophy, Letters and Social Science. Benjamin Werne (Ed.): vol. 1, no. 1, February 1934 (Box 1, Folder 75)
- Absorption of Immigrants by Arthur Saul Super, Israel Today: no. 18, February 1961 (Box 1, Folder 76)
- The American Rabbi: vol. 1, no.1, September 1961 (Box 1, Folder 77)
- Jewish Life: vol. 31, no. 5, May-June 1964 (Box 1, Folder 78)
- The Vanishing American Jew, B'nai Brith Current Issue Series: no. 171, c. 1963-1969 (Box 1, Folder 79)
- America: vol. 128, no. 9, March 10, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  Published by the Jesuits of the United States and Canada.
- Lilith: vol. 1, no.1, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 81)
- Between Us (Beineinu): vol. 8, no. 3, February 1978 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  A Journal published for members of The Rabbinical Assembly, Bernard S. Raskas (ed.)
- Ultimate Issues: vol. 8, no. 1, January-March 1992 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  A Quarterly Journal by Dennis Prager
- Present Tense: vol. 7, no.2, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 84)
- Jewish Life: vol. 3, no. 4, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 85)
- Revue Des Etudes Juives Historia Judaica: vol. 122, no. 1-2 and vol. 125, no. 1-3, 1963, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 86)
  Vol. 122: Rosenbloom, Noah H. "Hegelian Juridical Dialectics as a Matrix for Jewish Law"
  Vol. 125: Liebreich, L.J. "The Benediction Immediately Preceeding and the One Following the Recital of the Shema"
- Off-print from Hebrew Union College Annual vol. 27, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 87)
- Jewish Libel Action at Berne, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 88)
  Pamphlet published by The Right Cause Publishing Company, Chicago, 1935, subtitled "An Account of the Latest Jewish Attempt to Disavow Their Authorship of the Protocols with the Aid of False Witnesses and Miscarriage of Justice"
  Includes explanatory note describing 1935 Berne court case challenging the authenticity of the Protocols of Zion
- Zur Hochzeit von Ketty Felsenstein und David Goldshmidt, February 21, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 89)
  Printed collection of poems commemorating the 1922 wedding of Ketty Felsenstein and David Goldschmidt, attributed to "unserer geliebten seligen Mutter Gertrud Marx" [our beloved, blessed mother, Gertrud Marx]
- The Letter to the Hebrews or A First-Century Manual for Church Renewal in the Koinonia "Cotton Patch" Version, June 1963 (Box 1, Folder 90)
  Translation copyrighted by Clarence L. Jordan, Koinonia Farm, Americus, Georgia. Order forms for Koinonia Partners pamphlets included in folder.
- Din ve-heshbon shel hevrat Mekitse nirdamim li-shenat 700, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 91)
  Jerusalem: 1940
- I. Edward Kiev Judaica Collection brochure, September 2011 (Box 1, Folder 92)
- Open House: An Introduction to the Treasures of the I. Edward Kiev Judaica Collection, September 22, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 93)
  Exhibit brochure.
- Spinoza and Jewish Modernity: An Exhibit Marking the Publication of The First Modern Jews: Spinoza and the History of an Image (Princeton, 2012) by Daniel B. Schwartz, February 2012 (Box 1, Folder 94)
  I. Edward Kiev Collection exhibit brochure.
- Words Like Sapphires: 100 Years of Hebraica at the Library of Congress, 1912-2012 (Box 1, Folder 95)
- From German Wissenschaft to Global Scholarship: Jewish Historiography between the World Wars (Michael Brenner), 2010 (Box 1, Folder 96)
  The Leo Baeck Memorial Lecture #53. New York: Leo Baeck Institute, Inc.
- Why are Jews Persecuted for their Religion? The Truth is Stranger than Fiction!, Undated (Box 1, Folder 97)
  Bremerton, Washington: American Publishing Society
- Study and Prayer: Their Relative Value in Hasidism and Mitnagdism (Norman Lamm), reprinted from Samuel K. Mirsky Memorial Volume, undated (Box 1, Folder 98)
  New York: Yeshiva University and Jerusalem: Sura Institute for Research
- Antiquariaat Spinoza: Spinozana Catalogue 106, c. 2000-2012 (Box 1, Folder 99)
  Catalogue of items offered for sale, including "400 items, among which the library of Albert Kloezen". Two copies included in folder.
- Together (B'Yachad): The Newsletter of the Jewish National Fund, c. 2012 (Map-folder 100)
- Catalogue for the International Book Fair. Szonja Ráhel Komoróczy, ed., February, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 101)
  Jerusalem: Dov Sadan Publishing Project. English and Hebrew.
- A Brochure of Illustrious Jews and Jewesses, c. 1905 (Box 1, Folder 102)
  New York: Funk & Wagnalls, c. 1905.
- The Silver Objects from Czech Synagogue, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 103)
  Exhibit brochure. Prague: The State Jewish Museum in Prague, 1979.
- The End of the Jewish Town of Prague, by Jan Jungmann, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 104)
  Text in English, German, French, Italian, and Czech. Prague: Schola Ludus Pragensia, 1991.
- The Synagogue of Dohány Street, by Alfréd Schöner, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 105)
  Text in English and Hebrew. Budapest: BZSH in co-operation with Optimum Publishing, 1992.
  Several undated items found tucked inside this booklet: "Don't Forget the Victims" (pamphlet discussing Budapest memorial to Hungarian Jewish Holocaust victims), "The Chosen Tours" (brochure offering tours of Hungary's Jewish heritage), "Dohány Street Synagogue Interior" (postcard), and "Memorial Martyrs" (postcard).
- Memory and Action: United States Holocaust Memorial Museum Magazine, Spring 2013 (Box 1, Folder 106)
  Washington, DC: United States Holocaust Memorial Museum, 2013.
- Antiquariaat Spinoza List 103: Jewish Bibliography and other Reference Works, October 2011 (Box 1, Folder 107)
  Amsterdam: Antiquariaat Spinoza, 2011.
- Yad Ben-Zvi Press Catalogue of Publications, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 108)
  Jerusalem: Ben-Zvi Institute for the Study of Jewish Communities in the East, 2001.
- La Cucina Tradizionale Degli Ebrei Di Venezia, by Enzo Marconi, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 109)
  Catania: Libreria Tirelli di F. Guaitolini, 1929.
- Ausstellung der hebräischen Bestände für die Internationale Ökumenische Konferenz der Hebräischlehrenden (IÖKH), Heike Tröger, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 110)
- Jerusalem brochure, c. 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 111)
  Gift of Dr. Samuel Halperin.
- Jerusalem: Jewish Sites in and Around the City of David, c. 1970-1989 (Box 1, Folder 112)
- Jerusalem Tourist Map, c. 1970-1989 (Box 1, Folder 113)
- Taxation in Tel Aviv (Exhibit brochure), c. 1970-1989 (Box 1, Folder 114)
- Tower of David Museum: Where Jerusalem Begins, c. 1980-1989 (Box 1, Folder 115)
- Beth She'arim Visitor's Guide, from Historical Sites in Israel, 1968-1989 (Box 1, Folder 116)
  Published by the Government Tourist Corporation, Jerusalem, Israel. Gift of Dr. Samuel Halperin.
- Acre Municipal Museum, 1968-1989 (Box 1, Folder 117)
- The Jewish Museum in Prague, Precious Legacy Tours brochure, c. 1994 (Box 1, Folder 118)
- Jewish Monuments in Bohemia and Moravia, c. 1994 (Box 1, Folder 119)
  Published by the Czech Tourist Authority. Gift of Dr. Samuel Halperin.
- "We are the Wall Itself" Serigraphs by Albert Garvey, Spertus Museum, Chicago (exhibit postcard), 1978 (Box 1, Folder 120)
- Hermann Struck (1876-1944): Portraits and Landscapes from Europe to Palestine, Mizel Museum of Judaica, Denver, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 121)
- Pilgrimage to the Holy Lad: The Travelers' Maps, 1482 to the Present, Weiner Judaic Museum, Rockville, MD, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 122)
- Among the Nations: Jewish Tradition and the Diaspora Experience, B'nai B'rith Klutznick Museum and Beth Hatefutsoth, Washington, DC, c. 1980 (Box 1, Folder 123)
- "Pilgrimage to Israel" brochure, c.1980 (Box 1, Folder 124)
  Published by the Israel Ministry of Tourism, Jerusalem. Gift of Dr. Samuel Halperin.
- Pesach: The Fifth Cup, Undated (Box 1, Folder 125)
- The Political World of American Zionism by Samuel Halperin (publisher's order form), c. 1961 (Box 1, Folder 126)
  Folder includes two copies. Gift of Dr. Samuel Halperin.
- A Guide for the Powerless and those Wose Don't Know their Own Power: A Mini-Manual on the American Political Process by Samuel Halperin, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 127)
  Published by The Institute for Educational Leadership, Washington, DC. Gift of Dr. Samuel Halperin. Inscription on title page reads "GWU students taught me much about grassroots politics. I am grateful to each teacher. Samuel Halperin."
- Defense of the Holy Land, from A Thought for the Week, adapted from the works of Rabbi Menachem M. Schneerson by Yitschak M. Kagan, Undated (Box 1, Folder 128)
  Published by Vaad L'Hafotzas Sichos, Brooklyn, NY. Gift of Dr. Samuel Halperin.
- The Palestinian National Covenant (1968): An Israeli Commentary by Y. Harkabi, c. 1969 (Box 1, Folder 129)
  Offrint of December 12, 1969 Maariv article. Gift of Dr. Samuel Halperin.
- Maps of the Promised Land, Howard I. Golden, New York (sales catalog), 1983 (Box 1, Folder 130)
- Catalogue of Ancient Maps and Prints: Jerusalem and the Holy Land, Terra Sancta Arts Ltd., Tel Aviv (sales catalog), Undated (Box 1, Folder 131)
- Oettingen Haggadah Facsimile Edition Published by Nahar and Am Oved (publisher's order form), 1985 (Box 1, Folder 132)